Hi guys!
Today it's "Annyeong" instead of "Annyeong-haseyo".
Hi
Today, I'm not using formal language; I'm using informal language.
Informal language
Are you surprised?
Are you really surprised?
But why am I suddenly speaking informally today?
Does anyone know why?
I'll give you a hint.
It was April 1st recently.
April 1st
What day is it?
It's April Fools' Day!
In Korean, we call it "Manujeol".
People play a lot of pranks on April Fools' Day.
And they tell a lot of lies.
Lies
That's why I'm speaking informally today.
I'm only going to do it for today.
Only today
I'll speak informally just for today.
Some people call me "Teacher".
Teacher Ria
But today, let's just talk like we're friends.
Let's use informal language like close friends.
Got it?
In Korea, there's something called "Yaja Time".
Yaja Time
It's the name of a game.
Normally, you use formal language when you first meet.
And younger people use formal language to older people.
Older people use informal language to younger people.
But in "Yaja Time", this is reversed.
Opposite
For example, I would use informal language to a professor.
To a professor: "Hey Professor, where are you going?"
Instead of "Where are you going, Professor?", you say "Where you going?".
It's so scary.
Just imagining it is so scary.
Then on the flip side, the professor says "Ria-nim, where are you going?" to me.
That's the game.
Isn't it so fun?
Usually, when playing this game, younger people really like it.
They find it super fun.
Conversely, older people get "angry".
Angry
Why would they be angry?
They feel offended because a younger person is speaking informally to them.
It's like, "How dare you speak informally to me?".
But since it's a game, they aren't truly angry; it's just like a prank.
Is there an idol you like?
Then try searching "group name + Yaja Time" on YouTube.
You'll probably be able to find most of them.
The easiest way to speak informally is to drop the "yo".
Ban-ga-wo-yo (Nice to meet you) - Ban-ga-wo
Bap meog-eoss-eo-yo? (Did you eat?) - Bap meog-eoss-eo?
Now you guys try practicing too.
Mwo jo-a-hae-yo? (What do you like?) - Mwo jo-a-hae?
Hang-uk-eo gong-bu-hae-yo? (Do you study Korean?) - Hang-uk-eo gong-bu-hae?
And the most important thing is the name!
It's when you call someone's name.
When using formal language, you say Ria-nim or Teacher Ria, right?
But when speaking informally, you use "ya" like Ria-ya, or "a" if there is a bottom consonant.
Like "Ji-eun-a".
And when you don't want to say their name, just use "Ya".
Just say "Ya"
Hey, what are you doing?
But this is really casual informal language.
Usually, you use the name with "a/ya".
Do you guys like informal language or formal language when speaking Korean?
But you might not get many chances to hear informal language.
Might not have many chances
You can hear it in K-dramas or on YouTube.
You can hear it though
But on broadcasts, they mostly use formal language.
Usually, I use informal language a lot when I'm close or comfortable with someone.
Then, if you're the same age, do you automatically use informal language?
No.
Even if you're the same age, you almost always use formal language when you first meet.
Of course, really young kids don't know about this.
So when they first meet, they say "Hi, what's your name?" in a cute way.
Let me tell you about the process of how Koreans start using informal language.
Just when and how exactly do we start speaking informally?
First, you greet each other when you first meet.
"Annyeong-haseyo"
Then you introduce yourself.
You say your name... and then Koreans ask about age.
"By the way, how old are you?"
If the other person is older than me.
Then usually the younger person says this first.
"Uh... please speak comfortably"
Please speak comfortably
They say it like this
Please speak comfortably?
Speech is comfortable?
What does this mean?
Yep, that's right! it means to speak informally.
Of course, you could just say "It's okay to speak informally".
But we say "Please speak comfortably" really often.
It's a very natural Korean expression.
Or, "Drop your speech."
"You can drop your speech."
We say it like this really often.
Drop your speech? It's the same.
It means to speak informally.
You've just confirmed each other's ages.
But just because I'm older, suddenly speaking informally is a bit... awkward, right?
So usually the younger person asks first.
Asks first
"Please speak comfortably to me."
"You can drop your speech."
Then how does the older person respond?
Honestly, this varies a lot from person to person.
Everyone is different
Some people drop their speech immediately.
"Sure, got it. You speak comfortably, too."
Once that happens, you both start speaking informally.
Or they just say "Okay, got it."
Then the younger person keeps using formal language.
Only the older person speaks informally to me.
This is how we decide.
What about you guys?
If someone says "Please speak comfortably" or "Drop your speech" to you, will you speak informally?
Some Koreans find informal language a bit uncomfortable.
They find it a bit awkward.
Find it awkward
But I love informal language!
Because honestly, it feels like there's a wall when using formal language.
Wall
And there are so many things to be careful about with formal language.
Too many things to be careful about
You guys know, right?
You know how complex Korean formal language is, right?
Especially with grandmas, grandpas, or particularly professors who are much older than me.
I'm very careful when speaking in front of a professor.
I have a lot to say about professors, but I'll tell you about it later.
But I'm so comfortable when speaking informally.
And I feel like I've really become close to the person.
It varies by person, but I think you have to speak informally to be "real friends".
Not just someone you meet at work or see once in a while, but a real friend.
I feel our hearts getting closer.
But I said it earlier, right?
Some Koreans find informal language a bit awkward.
"Are we close enough to speak informally?"
"I don't think we're quite there yet."
That's the kind of vibe.
Of course, people don't actually say that out loud.
But they think it to themselves.
Inwardly
Let me tell you my story.
I met someone a long time ago.
Met for the first time
Like I said before, we told each other our ages.
The person was three years older than me.
So I said, "Please speak comfortably. You can drop your speech."
They replied, "It's okay. I'll drop it slowly later."
Since I like informal language, I was a bit bummed.
Bummed
Anyway, everyone is different like this.
The second reason I like informal language is... well, it's just cute.
"Bap meog-eoss-eo-yo? Mwo meog-eoss-eo-yo?"
Vs "Bap meog-eoss-eo? Mwo meog-eoss-eo?"
Which one is more comfortable and cute?
I think informal language is a bit cuter.
I like it because when speaking informally, it sounds cuter and I feel closer and more comfortable with the person.
Well, anyway, I did my first and last informal podcast like this today.
Or should I speak informally like this on next year's April Fools' Day too?
If you guys like it, I'll do it.
And this kind of casual, comfortable Korean.
This kind of Korean informal language that can be used between really close friends, boyfriends, and girlfriends!
If you're really interested in informal language, check out my channel's membership videos.
I occasionally post what I really want to say informally without a script.
I said it before, right?
I always speak informally with people I'm really close to.
At first, you have to learn formal Korean.
So normally, I post formal language videos.
Anyway, today was a podcast with an informal language concept.
I hope you guys liked it!
If you know how to use informal language in Korean, leave a comment in informal language.
You can say anything
Well, bye!
See you next time! Bye :)